你好，安妮
怎么
Yeah?
不 我们今天离开戛纳
No, no. No, we're leaving cannes now.
布达佩斯太大了
Hey, Budapest could be huge for us.
他们要求我们减半制片成本
They say we'll cut production costs in half!
不 假期可以等
No, a vacation can wait.
嗯 安妮知道 她理解
Yeah, Annie knows. She understands.
对了 今天早上我和山本先生见过面
Oh, right, I met with Mr. Yamamoto this morning.
他终于答应了我们的交易
He finally said yes to our deal.
我鞠躬 差点伤了老腰
Yeah. I almost threw my back out bowing.
OK 再会
Okay, later.
你绝想不到
You have no idea
这顿海鲜早餐的回味有多么...
how good this tastes after seaweed and fish.
日本分销商就不能只吃牛角面包么?
Why can't the Japanese distributors just serve croissants?
我们可是在法国 老天
I mean, we're in France, for Christ sakes.
需要来杯可口的冷咖啡吗?
Can I offer you some delicious cold coffee?
让我想想
Let me see. Oh...
我要继续打包
I gotta keep packing.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我没事 只是我的耳朵
Oh, I'll be fine, it's just my ears, you know.
好吧
Right.
拜托 100匹骆驼?
Oh, come on, 100 camels?
老天 我们上哪找100匹骆驼?
Where the hell are we gonna get 100 camels, for Christ sakes?
剧本怎么写的?
What does the script say?
山羊 我也这么想 摩洛哥山羊很便宜
Goats. I thought so. And those Moroccan goats work cheap.
你告诉导演 别再乱发挥创造力了
You tell the director, no more creativity.
他必须用那些该死的山羊...
He's gonna use the goddamn goats...
他能保住饭碗就算很幸运了 OK?
And he's lucky he still has a job. Okay?
我有没有提过境外制片是个鸟?
Have I mentioned that overseas production is a bitch?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
不会吧 一瓶水要12欧元
Seriously, 12 Euros for a bottle of water.
酒店索取你一个汉堡包加芝士三明治的钱
And look, they charged you for a hamburger and a cheese sandwich.
我想吃芝士汉堡 但菜单没有这种...
Well, I wanted a cheeseburger, but I couldn't order one...
所以我各定一个 自己混合一份
So, I got both and I made my own.
亲爱的 你工作这么努力
Honey, what are you working so hard for
你妻子想要一个芝士汉堡都不成么
if your wife can't have a cheeseburger when she wants one?
宝贝 我会给你买10亿芝士汉堡
Baby, I'd buy you a billion cheeseburgers,
但你知道 我有多讨厌铺张浪费
but you know how much i hate wasteful extravagance.
是的 连你的袖扣都是便宜货
Ah, yes. Because your cufflinks were such a bargain.
你看到那本书吗?我..
Have you seen that book I, uh...
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我看看那些小耳朵
Now let me check those little ears.
太贴心了
So sweet.
OK 我马上下来
Yeah. Okay. I'll be right down.
亲爱的 你能打电话给行李员吗?
Honey, would you call the bellman?
让他上来扛我的行李
Have him come up and get my bags.
很抱歉 所有线路忙
We're sorry,  all lines are busy.
对不起
Excuse me.
借过
Oh, sorry.
夫人 我很抱歉
Madame, I'm so sorry.
你能把这些记在洛克伍德名下吗?
Would you please hold this under lockwood?
谢谢 不客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
我实践了真正的梦想
It was my real dream to act.
我七年前去了巴黎
And so I went to Paris seven years ago.
一次美妙的经历
And it was a wonderful experience.
很高兴认识你
It's a pleasure to meet you. Oh.
我喜欢和你交谈 祝你好运
I enjoyed talking to you. Good luck.
很高兴见到你
Pleasure to meet you, too.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
你好 安妮
Bonjour, Anne.
你好 雅克
Hello, Jacques.
都准备好了 车子已经等着了
You're all set. I've checked you out and the car is waiting.
你看起来很可爱 是不是?
You look lovely. She does, doesn't she?
拜托
Come on.
洛克伍德先生 能拍张照吗?
Mr. lockwood, can I have a photo?
谢谢
Thank you.
你的司机来了
Your driver is here.
我看了剧本
I read the script.
如何?
Yes?
我告诉你 稍微带点经典
And I'm telling you, it could be a little classic,
也很商业
and it's commercial, too.
经典加商业片?我们赶紧制片吧
Classic and commercial? Come on. Let's go produce it!
等一分钟
Only for a minute.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
迈克尔 你知道我不爱发牢骚 但我的耳朵...
Oh, Michael, you know I am not a whiner, but my ears...
宝贝 对不起 一到布达佩斯
Oh, baby, I'm sorry. You'll be able to rest
你尽管休息
when we get to Budapest.
坚持到宾馆
And wait till you see where we're staying.
是马里奥 我的裤内缝长是多少?
It's Mario. Uh, what's my inseam?
34英寸
34 inches.
86厘米
86 centimeters. Ah.
飞机餐不算食物 我给你带了点好东西
The food on the plane will not be food. So i got you something good.
尝尝这香肠
Try this sausage.
老店家自己做的
The old man in that shop makes it himself.
看看这个第戎芥末
And look at this dijon mustard.
埃德蒙洛名厂制造 法国最好的
It's Edmond fallot. The best in France!
安妮 你的耳朵滴剂
Anne, here are some drops for your ears.
谢谢你 雅克
Thank you, Jacques.
我们的摩洛哥导演完全疯了
Our director in Morocco has gone completely crazy.
他每天加班两次
He's into double overtime every day.
他引诱女主角 现在他们在片场闹翻了
He seduced his leading lady but now they're fighting on the set.
噩梦
It's a nightmare.
是的 问题他执导了三部榜首电影
Yes, but he's had three straight hits.
放松 我们可以信任他
Relax, we can trust him.
他做什么?
What's he doing now?
我不知道
I don't know.
闻闻香味
Smell that perfume!
富含维他命
And it's full of vitamins!
谢谢 不客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
我真不敢相信拉斯居然派飞机
I can't believe laszlo sent this.
我告诉过你 他想和我们做生意
I told you he wants to be in business with us.
小心点 因为他可不是个大方的人
Be careful, because he's not a generous man.
夫人 - 请说?
Madame. Yes?
我注意到你耳朵好像不舒服
I notice your ears seem to be bothering you.
是的
Well, yes.
我得警告你 机舱压力会造成疼痛
I must warn you that the cabin pressure can be quite painful.
我不建议你今天搭乘飞机
I don't recommend you fly today.
谢谢
Thank you.
迈克尔 我想我应该跳过布达佩斯
Michael, I think i should skip Budapest
直接去巴黎
and just go straight to Paris.
什么?
What?
对
Yeah.
我是说 反正你是去工作的
I mean, you're gonna be working the whole time anyway.
亲爱的 我很抱歉 我不知道你感觉这么难过
Well, honey, I'm just sorry i didn't know you were feeling so bad.
我可以提个建议吗?
May I make a suggestion?
我会照顾她的
I'll take care of her.
真的?是的
Really? Yes.
我明早去巴黎开会
I have meetings tomorrow morning in Paris
我现在开车返回
and I'm driving back now.
没关系 我可以坐火车
Oh, that's fine. I can take the train, it's fine.
今天大家都离开戛纳 火车满了
Everybody's leaving cannes today. The trains are full.
让我开车送你吧
So, let me drive you. Uh...
真慷慨
That's very generous,
你确定没问题吗?
but you sure it's okay with you?
呃
Uh...
大约晚餐时间到
You'll be there by dinner time.
听着 我不咬人
Look, I don't bite.
你在巴黎休息 - 今晚等我电话
You rest up in Paris. - I'll call you tonight.
宝贝 我爱你
Baby, I love you. Uh...
请等一下
Hold on one second please.
我得走了 再见
I gotta go. Bye.
迈克尔
Michael!
可爱的小汽车
This is a lovely car.
是的 我们在一起很久了
Yes. She's with me for a long time. Hmm.
不 你需要吃午饭 走吧
No, no, no, no. You need lunch. Come.
到了
Oh. Here.
我在戛纳的时候 喜欢呆在这里
I like to stay here when I'm in cannes,
远离海滩上的人群
away from the crowd at the beach.
今天天气很好
It's a beautiful day.
你紧张吗?
Are you nervous?
也许 一点点
Maybe. A little bit.
我们从来没有单独一起过
We've never actually been alone together.
刚才我说不咬人的时候 你没有相信我
So you didn't believe me when I said I don't bite.
你想喝杯酒吗?
Uh, would you like a glass of wine?
不
No, no.
不 谢谢
No, no. Thank you.
好吧
Yes!
既然是法国
When in France.
你会喜欢这酒的新堡干红
You'll like this wine, it's chateauneuf-du-pape.
很好味
Ooh. That's good!
谢谢
Merci.
这酒与火腿和甜瓜很配
This wine goes well with your ham de bayonne and melon.
谢谢
Merci.
真好吃
It's delicious! Mmm.
有点粗鲁 但是安妮 我可能需要接电话
I know it's rude, but, Anne, I may have to take some calls.
没关系 我已经习惯了
It's okay. I'm used to it.
不必抱歉
You shouldn't be.
安妮 交易要约就像蛋奶酥 时机要好
Anne, a deal offer is like a souffle. It's all about timing.
是啊 塌下来就不好了
Yes, you don't want it to collapse.
请说?
Yes?
不 告诉他我不入 除非英国入30%
No, tell him I'm not in unless the uk comes in for 30%.
那就叫他见鬼去吧
Well, then, tell him to go to hell!
OK?
Okay?
失陪一下
Excuse me a minute. Mmm.
安妮 我需要信用卡 你有吗?
Anne, I need a credit card. Do you have one?
你不是有信用卡吗?
Don't you have a credit card?
我有很多
Oh, I have many.
我以后再解释
I explain later.
OK
Okay.
只用于酒店预授权
Just to hold the hotel reservation until we get there.
你是说酒店吗?
Did you say hotel?
是的
Yes.
雅克 我们要去巴黎的
Jacques, we're going to Paris.
当然 但你需要休息
Of course, of course, but you need rest.
有一家很好的客栈和餐厅
There is a fine inn with an excellent restaurant.
现在是松露季节
And it's truffle season!
门坏了?
It doesn't work?
我开门
I need to open the door for you. Oh.
耳朵怎么样?
So how are your ears?
我希望那些滴剂能帮上忙 谢谢
Oh, I hope those drops will help. Thank you.
莫扎特 好的不要不要的
Mozart, we couldn't do better.
假装我们不知道要去哪里
So let's pretend we don't know where we're going
也不知道我们是谁
or even who we are.
大哥喂
Oh, brother.
看到那边那座山吗?
Oh. You see that mountain over there?
有 - 圣维克多尔山
Yeah. It's St. victoire.
注意前方卡车
Do you see that truck right in front of us!
那山是本地区的主要地标
It's a major landmark of this region,
也是许多作家和艺术家最喜欢的题材
and a favorite subject for many writers and artists.
塞尚完美地捕捉到它
Cezanne captured it perfectly.
去年我在艾克斯看了他作品的绝美展览（普罗旺斯地区）
I saw a beautiful exhibition of his work last year in aix-en-provence.
真棒 - 对
That's great. Yeah.
从这个角度看到塞尚的画
Oh, it must have been incredible to see
绝对不可思议
cezanne's paintings here in this light.
我认识的纽约人 他们有点伤感
The ones that I know at the met in New York, they look a little sad.
好像他们并不真的想去那里
You know, as if they don't really want to be there.
我喜欢每小时休息一下
I like to stop about every hour.
伸伸腿 抽根烟
Stretch my legs and have a cigarette.
已经42分钟了
It's been 42 minutes.
对
Yeah.
她渴了
She gets thirsty.
我希望吸烟不会打扰你
I hope my smoking isn't bothering you.
实际上 让我想起了我父亲
Ah. Actually it reminds me of my father.
他每天抽两包骆驼烟
He smoked two packs of camel cigarettes a day.
他死于56岁
He died at 56.
看到那边的山顶了吗?
Oh. See that hilltop over there?
那些旧石墙和那座城堡?
See those old stone walls and that castle?
罗马人曾经经过此地
The romans were all through this area.
你知道这个地区被称为普罗旺斯
Did you know that this region is called provence
因为它曾是罗马的一个省?
because it was a province of Rome?
不 - 是的
No. Yes. Ha.
迈克尔和我从法国南部飞往巴黎
Michael and I have flown from the south of France to Paris,
但我们从没开车
but we've never driven.
开车是欣赏一个国家的唯一方法
Driving is the only way to see a country.
我一直想看到盛开的薰衣草
I've always wanted to see the lavender in bloom.
太美了
It's gorgeous!
我给你看点东西
I'll show you something.
安妮 我很高兴能和你在一起
Anne, you know, I'm happy to be here with you
因为这是我打小以来 第一次回来
because it's the first time I've come back here since I was a kid.
上帝
Oh, my god!
太不可思议了
Yeah. It's incredible.
这是高架渠的一部分 当罗马人...
It's part of an aqueduct built when the romans
高高掌权的时期
were at the height of their power,
只是为了打动他们的臣民
just to impress their subjects.
印象深刻
Well, I'm impressed.
2000年前? - 是的
Two-thousand years ago? Yeah.
伟大的石匠
They were great stonemasons.
人们在这条河上泛舟
People canoe on this river.
听起来很有趣
That sounds fun.
是的
Yeah.
我不记得迈克尔和我...
I can't remember the last time
最后一次下午逃学
Michael and I played hooky for the afternoon.
你得尝尝榛子味 很好吃
You've got to taste the noisette, nocciola. Mmm, it's great.
还得尝尝黑醋栗和草莓味
And you must try the cassis. And fraise des bois.
很不错
That's pretty good.
看 野生羽扇草
Look, wild lupine.
我们在加利福尼亚有野生羽扇
We have wild lupine in California.
是的 但是你不能吃
Oh, yes, but you can't eat them.
嗯 不能
Well, no.
野蒲公英
Look at the wild dandelions.
加少许橄榄油 压碎的凤尾鱼 盐和胡椒...
Mmm. With a little olive oil, crushed anchovies, salt and pepper...
就是了不起的沙拉
They make a marvelous salad.
我肯定罗马人吃过
I'm sure the romans ate them.
什么都和吃有关吗?
Does everything remind you of eating?
是的
Yes.
请停一下 光线完美
Stay, please. The light is perfect.
转一下
Yeah? Turn a little.
现在差不多了
Oh, yes. Now come in close.
太棒了
It's great.
丫
Oh, yeah.
埃里克·萨蒂 他是一个非常古怪的人
This is Erik satie. He was a very eccentric man.
你知道他从来不洗衬衣吗?
Did you know he never washed his shirts?
他妻子洗?
So, his wife did them?
不 他没有妻子
No, he did not have a wife.
没有?
No?
没有 不是每个人都愿意有妻子的
No, not everyone has to have a wife to be happy.
所以 他的衬衣脏了 就扔掉
So, when his shirts got dirty, he just threw them away.
雅克 - 请说?
Jacques. Yeah?
我不是法国人
I'm not French.
没错 请吧
Yes, that is correct. Please.
晚餐预定在45分钟后 你能准备好吗?
Our dinner reservation is in 45 minutes. Can you be ready?
楼下见 - OK
I'll meet you downstairs. Okay.
晚上好 夫人 - 晚上好
Bonsoir, madame.  Bonsoir.
你好
Hi!
我在想你
I was thinking about you.
你在想什么?
Yeah, what were you thinking?
你可爱的小耳朵
About your sweet little ears.
巴黎怎么样?
So how's Paris?
其实我还没到
I'm actually not there yet.
怎么了?
Why, what happened?
没什么 雅克想停下来过夜
Nothing, really. Jacques wanted to stop for the night.
他什么?
He what?
听着 他不是最伟大的司机
Look, he's not the greatest driver.
可能件好事 我们不用赶夜路
It's probably a good thing we're not on the roads after dark.
是的 别忘了
Yeah.  Hey, don't forget,
他是法国人
he's a frenchman.
布达佩斯怎么样?
How's Budapest?
酒店很棒  多瑙河景色壮观
The hotel is great.  It has an amazing view of the danube.
你感觉怎么样? - 好多了
How are you feeling? Better.
那些滴剂真的很有帮助
Those ear drops are really helping.
什么耳朵滴剂?
What ear drops?
迈克尔 我们去度真正的假期 只我们两个
Michael, let's go on a real vacation, just the two of us.
是的 我的电话没被邀请
Yeah, my phone not invited.
亲爱的 我又腰疼了
Honey, I think I'm getting  my back thing again.
你知道我的药包在哪里?
Do you know where  my pill pack is?
箱子的口袋里
It's in the pocket of your kit.
我看过了
I looked there.
在有拉链的里面
It's on the inside zip one.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
你最好了
You're the best.
你明天什么时候能到巴黎?
Uh, what time do you think  you'll get to Paris tomorrow?
我想是下午早些时候吧
Early afternoon, I guess.
好 到了就给我打电话 爱你
Okay. Call me when  you get there. Love you.
我也爱你
All right. Love you, too.
对不起 我不会说法语
I'm sorry, i don't speak French.
对不起 他说什么?
I'm sorry. What did he say?
他说: "你很幸运能和雅克一起吃饭"
He said, "you're very lucky to be having dinner with Jacques."
这里的厨师以烤小羊羔出名
The chef here was famous for roast baby lamb.
你看中什么 安妮?
What looks good to you, Anne?
一切都很好 我无法决定
Everything looks good. I can't decide.
你不必
You don't have to.
我已经饱了
I'm full already.
本地产葡萄酒有孔得里约和罗纳河谷
The wines of the region are condrieu and cote-rotie.
我们两种都要
We'll have them both.
看起来棒极了
This looks great!
迈克尔说 你关了服装店
So, Michael tells me you've closed your dress shop.
是的 我的合作伙伴和她丈夫搬到了伦敦
Yes. My partner moved to London with her husband.
我不能一个人经营 - 你怀念它吗?
I couldn't keep it open by myself. Do you miss it?
我怀念顾客们和所有的漂亮衣服
I miss our customers and all the pretty clothes.
但我准备尝试新的东西
But I'm ready to try something new.
你对什么有兴趣?
What interests you now?
我注意到 你拍了很多照片
I notice you take a lot of pictures.
只是为了好玩
Oh. Those are just for fun.
我要为我们的店铺公告拍照
I started taking photos for our shop announcements.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
我现在停不下来了
And now I can't stop.
现在
Now.
又一张
Another one. Oh.
我女儿阿历克斯 她小时候我经常这么做
I did this with our daughter, Alexandra, when she was little.
我记得她 她喜欢穿你的红鞋子
I remember her. She liked to wear your red shoes.
你还记得?
You remember that?
是的
Yeah.
那双鞋还在
I still have those shoes.
你最后一次穿是什么时候?
So when was the last time you wore them?
她现在多大了?
How old is she now?
她18岁
She's 18.
她高中毕业的照片
Here's a picture of her high school graduation.
她现在在加州圣巴巴拉
She's at u.C. Santa Barbara, now.
这是她离家后的第二学期
It's her second semester away from home.
可爱的眼睛
She has lovely eyes...
就像她妈妈
Like her mother.
她母亲想要工作孩子两不误 所以照顾她...
Her mother is so used to juggling work and taking care of her...
我不知道自己该怎么办
I don't know what I'm gonna do with myself.
但你有很多选择
But you have so much to offer.
现在对你来说 是个好时机
It's a great time for you now.
是吗? - 当然
It is? Yes, of course.
你凭何手舞足蹈?
What makes you dance in the street?
因为你漂亮 引人兴趣
You're beautiful. You're an interesting woman.
拜托
Oh, come on.
我看到戛纳的所有男人都对年轻女孩垂涎三尺
I saw all the men in cannes drooling over those young girls.
拜托 他们只是果酱吐司饼干
Come on. They're just pop-tarts.
你是巧克力奶油布丁
You, you're chocolate creme brulee.
对 就是你 布丁
Yes, that's you. Brulee.
我给你介绍安妮
Oh, let me introduce you to Anne.
我是卡洛 很高兴认识你
This is Carole. Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你 抱歉打扰了
Nice to meet you. Sorry for intruding.
我刚听说雅克在这里
I just heard that Jacques was here.
祝你用餐愉快
Enjoy your dinner.
谢谢
Thank you.
我以前来过这里 我熟识卡洛
I used to come here. I got to know Carole.
是的 很明显
Yeah, that was clear.
她是店主的侄女
She's the owner's niece.
当然
Of course.
为什么同样的花 法国的...
Why do flowers smell so much better in France
比美国的香?
than they do in the us?
为什么?因为我们在法国
Why? Because we're in France.
在美国 看起来很可爱 但闻起来像冰箱
In America they look lovely but they smell like a refrigerator.
是真的 - 对
It's true. Yeah.
还有
Well...
我最喜欢的玫瑰
Roses are my favorite.
是 但玫瑰香不会影响葡萄酒的香气
Yes, but their scent mustn't intrude on the aroma of the wine.
你知道是罗马人
Did you know that it was the romans
首先在法国酿酒的?
who started winemaking in France?
我不知道 你导游
I did not know that, my tour guide.
呜啦啦?
Ooh, la, la?
你会知道的
You'll see.
"皇家海鲷"(法语)指的是"鲷鱼"
So dorade royale is what you call snapper.
牙齿像婴儿一样小
Mmm-hmm. It has little teeth like a baby
产自大西洋
and it comes from the Atlantic.
嗯 这裙子真漂亮 布丁
Mmm. That's a pretty dress, brulee.
是你店里的吗?
Is it from your store?
是法国的
Actually, it's French. Oh.
我对纺织品有热情
Normally I have a passion for textiles.
你还对什么有热情?
And what else do you have a passion for?
昂贵的首饰
Very expensive jewelry.
啊
Ah.
就像我看到你戴的漂亮手镯
Yeah, like that, uh, fancy bracelet i see you wearing.
这吗
That.
其实是巴塞罗那的主厨给我的
Actually this was given to me by a chef in Barcelona.
世界上最好的海鲜 新鲜藤壶 巨型螃蟹
We ate the best seafood in the world. Fresh barnacles, giant crabs.
他戴着它 以提醒自己 他卑微的出身
He wore it to remind himself of his humble beginnings,
像我们这样吃东西有多不寻常
and how extraordinary it is to be eating like we are.
我从不脱下来
I never take it off.
你想让我喝醉吗?太淘气了
Are you trying to get me drunk? That's naughty.
喝多少按感觉
Just drink what you feel like.
羊肉和小牛肉都是喂奶长大的
The lamb and the veal are milk fed.
这是一年中吃幼崽的最佳时间
This is the best time of the year to eat young animals.
是的 也是吃嫩胡萝卜的最佳时机
Yes, well it's also the best time to eat young carrots.
你为什么不结婚?
So, why have you never married?
我听说你有个女朋友
I heard you had a girlfriend
一个了不起的厨师 有自己的小餐馆
and she was a marvelous chef and she had her own little restaurant.
她听起来很适合你
She sounded perfect for you.
那是很久以前的事了
Well, uh, that was a long time ago.
怎么了?
Well, what happened?
我们很相互中意 但是
We were right for each other, but...
不幸的是 有些情况
Unfortunately, there were circumstances.
并非所有的事情都是命中注定的
Not all things are meant to be.
是的 爱并不总是公平的
Yes, well, love isn't always fair.
何解?
Why is that?
这对我来说是没有意义的
It will never make sense to me.
雅克 我不能再多吃了
Jacques, i can't eat much more.
这奶酪是用纯生牛奶做的
This cheese is made from  unpasteurized milk.
鲜活健康
It's alive and very healthy.
美国的奶酪经过巴氏杀菌 是死的
Your cheese in America is pasteurized. It's dead.
在胃里就像脂肪球
It goes into your stomach like a ball of fat.
所以你们法国人可以吃...
Is that why you French people can eat
任何黄油和奶酪
all the butter and cheese you want
却从不发胖?
and never gain weight?
对 我们喝更多的红酒
Yes, and we drink more red wine.
当然 我们更浪漫
Of course, we are more romantic.
是吗?
Oh. Is that so?
布丁 你知道我的恶习 抽烟
So, brulee, you know my vice, it's smoking.
现在说说你的(恶习)
Now you must confess yours.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
这是我最后一次告诉你实话
That is the last time i ever tell you the truth.
尝一下
Just taste.
按感觉吃就可以了
Mmm. Just eat what you feel like.
不像抽烟
You know, unlike smoking,
有研究说 巧克力对你有好处
there are studies that say that chocolate is good for you.
你们美国人总是理由一套一套的
You Americans always have to have a reason for everything.
我们想吃什么吃什么
We eat what we enjoy.
迈克尔在我们下楼吃饭之前 给我打了电话
Michael called me just before we came down for dinner.
他担心我们在一起
He's worried about us here together.
你呢?
Are you?
我应该吗?
Should I be?
我不知道
Well, I don't know.
漫长的婚姻中 你的孩子离开家后
In a long marriage, after your child leaves home...
你开心吗?
Are you happy?
我们的婚姻美满
We have a good marriage...
不 我没问你这个
No, that's not what I asked you.
你开心吗?
Are you happy?
嗯 当然
Well, sure.
有时
Sometimes.
从迈克尔的来电 他不知何故不信任我们
From Michael's call, i know that he somehow mistrusts us.
也许他不信任自己
Perhaps he mistrusts himself.
他忠诚吗?
Is he faithful?
你可能比我更了解
Oh, well, you probably know better than I.
他有相当的声誉...
He had quite a reputation and...
我们经历了一段艰难的时期
Well, we went through some hard times.
你是否向生活妥协了?
And have you made peace with your life?
这算什么问题?
What kind of question is that?
我认为这是个好问题
I think it's a good question.
你是否向自己妥协
Have you made peace with yourself
婚姻已然如此?
and your marriage the way it is?
别担心 没事的
Oh. Don't worry, it's okay.
我真是笨手笨脚
I'm such a klutz.
我们法国人 对婚姻有不同的态度
We French, we have a different attitude about marriage
相比你们美国人
than you Americans.
是什么?
Oh, and what is that?
我们务实
We are practical.
我们忠于家庭和婚姻
We're loyal to family and to marriage...
但我们是人类 我们遵循人类的自然激情
But we are human, and we follow our natural human passions.
好吧 我们对你们来说似乎乏味寡欲
Well, we must seem boringly puritanical to you.
还有内疚 内疚不利于消化菜
And guilty. Guilt is bad for your digestion.
那你说说 迈克尔是谁的菜?
Well, how would you say Michael's digestion is?
他是个有魅力的男人
Well... He's an attractive man,
女人迷上电影 也会做荒唐的事
and women do outrageous things to get into movies.
一次 某渴望成名的小明星来到我们的沙滩桌前
Once, a wannabe starlet came to our table at the beach.
迈克尔脱下了他的鞋子
Michael had taken off his shoes.
她挑了一只 在里面浇了香槟 向他敬酒
She picked one up, poured champagne in it and toasted him.
迈克尔感到她的绝望
Michael felt her desperation.
他把她送走时
So, as he sent her away,
他送上他的玫瑰金劳力士表
he gave her his rose gold rolex.
他不必这么做的
He didn't have to do that.
那块表是我给他的
I gave him that watch.
他说丢了
He told me he lost it.
对不起 我不是故意让你心烦的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to upset you.
你好 夫人
Bonjour, madame.
你好
Bonjour.
早上好 布丁
我不确定你喜欢饮咖啡、茶
或巧克力    像你这样的女人
拥有选择权待会儿见
雅克
苏珊
布达佩斯怎么样?
嘿 你好
Hey. Hi.
我没去
I didn't go.
我的耳朵疼死了 所以雅克开车送我去巴黎
My ears were killing me, so Jacques offered to drive me to Paris.
对不起?雅克?
Excuse me? Jacques?
迈克尔让你和"雅克"一起走?
Michael let you go  with a man named "Jacques"?
苏珊 拜托 迈克尔信任我
Suzanne, come on. Michael trusts me.
你要和雅克开车穿越法国 而不打电话给我?
You're driving across  France with Jacques, and you didn't call me?
你什么时候来接我?
When are you picking me up?
他是个调情高手 他吃得太多 他抽烟
He's a flirt. And he eats too much and he smokes.
我也是 看来我很合适
So do I. We're perfect  for each other.
他可爱吗?
Is he adorable?
是的 但我此行是为了和迈克尔共度一段时光
Yeah. But I came on this trip to spend some time with Michael.
是哈 看看你在哪里
Yeah, and look  where you are.
抓住时机
Seize the moment.
只要确保他不离开你
Just make sure  he doesn't leave you
滞留在路上的某处
stranded along  the road somewhere.
对
Yeah, right.
得走了 再见
Gotta go. Bye.
早上好 布丁
Good morning, brulee.
感觉如何?
So, how are you feeling?
好多了 谢谢
Much better, thank you.
我的耳痛几乎消失了 多亏了奇妙的耳朵滴剂
My earache's nearly gone thanks to those marvelous ear drops.
还有优质法国葡萄酒的药用品质
And the medicinal quality of fine French wine.
毫无疑问
Ha! No doubt.
热巧克力味道很好 谢谢
And the hot chocolate was a very nice touch, thank you.
我早饭从来不喝热巧克力
I haven't had any hot chocolate for breakfast
自从女童子军毕业后
since I was at girl scout camp.
你睡的怎么样?
How did you sleep?
挺好
Oh, well.
我注意到你没穿袜子
I noticed you're not wearing any socks.
你看穿了一切
Oh, yes. You see everything.
我没有打包 所以洗了穿着的那套
I didn't pack any so I washed the ones
还没干
I was wearing, but they are not dry.
我碰巧有迈克尔的衣物
Well, I happen to have some of Michael's.
他忘在旅馆了
He left them at the hotel.
你需要吗?
Would you like them?
好吧 为什么不呢?谢谢
Oh, well, why not. Thanks.
我明白"走别人的路 让别人无路可走 但是"穿别人的袜 让别人无袜可穿"?
I know what it means to walk in another man's shoes, but his socks?
我想付昨晚我房间的钱
I'd like to pay for my room last night.
事实上 如果你不介意 我需要你的信用卡
Actually, i need your credit card, if you don't mind.
再次?是的
Again? Yes.
我发现我的现金包裹回巴黎去了
I discovered my envelope of cash went back to Paris
我的助手搞错了
with my assistant by mistake.
所以我不得不把房间和餐费记在你的卡上
So I had to leave the charges of our rooms and dinner on your card.
OK
Okay.
我的名字在法国很常见
You know, my name is quite common in France,
不幸的是 很多同名者
and unfortunately, someone using the same name has been
用假卡骗钱
charging on false cards.
在问题解决之前 我必须用现金
Until it is fixed, i have to use cash.
我有足够的钱购买汽油和小东西  但酒店和晚餐不行
I have enough for gas and little things, but not for hotel and dinner.
我一到巴黎就给你报销
I will reimburse you as soon as we get to Paris.
好的
Right.
OK
Okay.
我有好消息
So I have good news.
我朋友在里昂给我们订了午餐
My friend got us a lunch reservation in Lyon
餐厅有新厨师 评论相当好
at the restaurant with a new chef who's got outstanding reviews.
雅克 听起来不错
Jacques, that sounds wonderful,
但我想我们现在应该在巴黎了
but I thought we'd be in Paris by now.
巴黎可以等待
Paris can wait.
我们不能不看金字塔就走
We can't leave without taking a look at the pyramid,
因为就在这里
as they call it here.
当然不能
Of course not.
2000年前 这标志着罗马竞技场的中心
Two-thousand years ago this marked the center of a Roman circus.
你能感觉到战车在赛跑吗
Can you feel the chariots racing
就在我们站的地方?
right here where we're standing?
太棒了 是的
That's so amazing! Yeah.
来吧 - 等等
Come. Wait.
它不是真正的金字塔 更像...
It's not really a pyramid, but, it's more...
方尖碑? - 是的
Obelisk? Yes.
鸟住在这里
Birds live in here.
你玩"我看看"游戏吗?
Do you play "i spy"?
听起来很危险
Sounds dangerous.
我和阿历克斯自驾时 一起玩的游戏
It's a game i used to play with Alexandra on road trips.
我看到四条腿
I spy something with four legs.
我看到两条美腿
I spy something with two lovely legs.
拜托
Come on.
游戏结束
Game over.
还没有
Not yet.
你到底去哪了?
Where the hell have you been? Oh!
附近有个朋友 她的花园满是玫瑰
A friend lives very nearby. She has a garden full of roses.
对不起
Excuse me.
请上车
Please, come in.
这趟旅程 车有余香
We'll have their perfume until the rest of our trip.
准备好了?
Ready?
现在是本地区旅行的绝佳时间
This is a perfect time to be traveling through this region.
罗纳河就在附近
The rhone river is nearby.
我们可以拐弯看看
We can turn off and have a look.
我们还去巴黎吗?
Are we ever going to get to Paris?
假设我们有一年的时间去巴黎
Let's pretend we have a year to get there.
大多数人没有意识到
Most of the people don't realize
有许多好吃的东西
there are many delicious things to eat
就在他们眼皮底下
growing right under their noses.
看 这是野茴香
Look, it's wild fennel.
钓鳟鱼 在河床上烧烤
Catch a trout, grill it on a bed of that,
有什么...
and you have something really...
上帝
Oh, my god!
怎么?
What?
我不知道怎么回事
I have no idea what's wrong.
这里是哪里 美丽的乡村
But look where we are, in this beautiful countryside!
我们去野餐吧
Let's have a picnic!
什么?
What?
雅克 我得去巴黎 我们有麻烦了
Jacques, i need to get to Paris, and we have a problem.
我们的问题哪儿也去不了
Our problem isn't going anywhere.
我从旅馆带了些东西
I brought a few things from the hotel.
走吧
Come on.
阿历克斯 亲爱的
Alex, honey,
一切都好吗?半夜了
is everything all right? It's the middle of the night there.
妈妈
Mom.
什么事?
What, what's the matter?
诺亚真是个混蛋
Noah is such a jerk!
什么?
What? What, what, what?
他终于约我出去
He finally asks me  to hang out,
约好在杜根酒吧
so, like,  I meet him at dugan's pub,
他居然带了两个瘾君子室友
and he brings his  two stoner roommates.
亲爱的 他可能有点紧张
Honey, he was probably just nervous.
男孩们不懂自己在做什么 哪怕大男孩
Boys don't always know what they're doing, not even big boys.
有时你需要带头
Sometimes you need to take the lead.
太差劲了
That's so lame.
我可以提醒你 这是你一生中最美好的时光吗?
May I remind you, this is a great time in your life?
妈妈 我听到鸟叫声
Mom, I hear birds.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
我和你爸爸的生意伙伴一起开车去巴黎
I'm driving to Paris with one of your dad's business partners.
听起来很无聊
Ugh. That sounds so boring.
天哪 你绝不知道
Oh, my god, you have no idea.
听着 我一直考虑你的生日 我有些主意
Look, I've been thinking about your birthday. I have some ideas.
是吗?OK
Yeah? Okay.
阿历克斯打电话来
Alex called.
她没事吧?
Is she okay?
她会的
Well, she will be.
关于男孩
It's about a boy.
我没有所有的答案
I don't have all the answers,
但我试着给她一些小建议
but I try to slip her a little advice when she lets me.
我觉得你有很多答案
I have a feeling you have a lot of answers.
野豆瓣菜 我刚找到的
See? Wild watercress. I just found it.
完美 不辛不辣
Mmm. It's perfect, not hot and peppery
比起本季末上市的时候
as it can get later in the season.
尝尝吧
Taste it.
不
Oh, no.
来吧 试试看
Come on, try it.
从大自然中直接品尝野生风味
Taste the wild flavor straight from nature.
很好
It's good.
看到没?
Ah. You see?
看啊
Look at that. Yeah.
还有这个
And this one here.
你刚做了一份五星级的野餐
So, you've just made a five-star picnic.
美妙
Wonderful.
尝尝这个
Try this.
等等
Oh, wait.
这太美了
This is so beautiful.
美味
Delicious.
车怎么办?
But what about the car?
她会等我们吃完饭的
She'll wait for us to eat.
全部试试
Try them all.
我不必尝试一切 来了解我喜欢什么
I don't need to try everything to know what I like.
这是我第一次尝试数独
It's the first time i tried sudoku.
我喜欢 但我被卡住了
I like it, but I got stuck.
教我你的技巧
Teach me your tricks.
你 找三链数
You, um, look for triplets.
看到图案没有?
You see the pattern?
嗯
Yeah?
找到它 一行有三个相同数
You can find it when you see three in a row.
我开始拼图
I start puzzles,
但我不知道 完成了有什么必要
but I'm not sure i have what it takes to finish them.
我想你知道
I think you do.
假装我们在那幅马奈的画里
You know, let's pretend we are in that manet painting,
"草地上的午餐"
le dejeuner sur l'herbe.
好的
Right.
看到吗?车还在等着呢
See? The car is still waiting.
现在我们有麻烦了
Now we have a problem.
我不认为是散热器
I don't think it's the radiator.
我也不知道
I wouldn't know.
你当然不会知道
Well, of course you wouldn't know.
下面没有吃的东西
There's nothing to eat under here.
上帝
Oh, my god.
哈哈
A-ha!
风扇皮带
Fan belt!
也
Well, yeah.
你有小刀吗?
Do you have your pocket knife?
有
Yeah.
好了 拿着
All right, here. Hold this.
转身
Turn around.
我曾经在YouTube上看到女人做过
Once I saw a woman on YouTube doing this.
当时看起来很简单
It looked simple at the time.
拿去
Here.
拿住那边
Take that side.
那边 OK
That one. Okay.
OK 你的拇指那里割断
Okay, cut it where your thumb is.
很好
All right.
右穿左
Right over left.
希望我做对了
I hope I did that right.
好吧 把这玩意
All right, you're gonna have to fit this
穿到风扇皮带所在
around where the fan belt goes.
试试看
The... Try it.
在哪?
Uh, where?
好吧 必须在那玩意下面
Well, it's gotta go under the thing.
OK 我看到了 在另一边
Okay, okay, I can see. Around the other side.
必须全部括住
It's gotta go over the whole thing.
现在又太松了
Now it's too loose.
刀拿来
I need your knife again.
我刚以为够了的
All right, I think i got that right.
也许差一点
Maybe not.
OK
Okay.
试试看
Try that.
全部包住了吗? - 是的
All the way. Is it all the way? Yeah.
好了 看看是否有效
It's okay. Let's see if actually it works.
你们美国女人很聪明
You American women are ingenious!
他说什么?
What's he say?
他说 "你是个很聪明的女人"
He said, "you're a very clever woman."
现在假装这车能直接开到巴黎
Now, let's pretend we're driving straight to Paris in a car that works.
而且一个月不需要吃喝
And we don't need another thing to eat or drink for a month.
这车的设计目的是让人失去食欲
This car is designed to make you lose your appetite.
它有安全气囊 我有音乐
Well, it has airbags. And I can play my music.
你肯定知道这个乐队 法国的
I'm sure you know this band. They're French.
阿历克斯给我的 她去好莱坞剧场看过演出
Alex gave this to me. She saw them play at the Hollywood bowl.
对 凤凰城
Yes, it's Phoenix.
我只希望我的车能浴火重生
Oh, I just hope my car can rise from the ashes.
这里是里昂
Well, this is Lyon.
法国的中心
We are in the heart of France.
我们离巴黎有多远?老实说
So how far are we from Paris? Be honest.
不远 我们先停一下
Not far. We have a stop first.
我的卢米埃尔
Well, this is l'institut lumiere,
卢米埃尔兄弟 他们曾住在这里
and the two lumiere brothers, they lived here
他们创造了电影艺术
when they invented cinematography.
导演是我的朋友
The director is a friend of mine.
雅克
Jacques!
安妮从美国一路过来参观你的博物馆
Anne has come all the way from America to see your museum.
呵呵
Well.
差不多啦
Almost.
我是安妮
I'm Anne.
马丁
Martine.
那我们走吧
Well, let's go, then.
安妮 马丁和我有事要谈
Anne, martine and i have business to discuss,
所以她安排了导游
so, she organized a tour for you.
好的
Oh. Yeah.
菲利普会带你参观博物馆
Philippe will show you our museum.
嗨 很高兴认识你
Hi, nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
请往这边走
Right this way, please.
请看
Then we'll move to this one.
这是活动电影机
This is, uh, the cinematographe,
第一台摄影机
which is the very first camera.
由路易斯和卢米埃尔在1895年发明
It was invented by Louis and auguste lumiere in 1895.
也是投影机
It is also a projector.
第一台大众投影机
And then you have a model of the first public projection.
卢米埃尔兄弟认为他们的发明没有前途
And the lumiere brothers, um, thought their invention had no future.
显然他们错了
Apparently they were wrong.
导游结束了
Well, that concludes our tour.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起 我得走了 但你可以参观礼品店
Um, I'm sorry, I have to go, but you're free to visit the gift shop.
祝你愉快 - 谢谢
Have a nice day. Thank you.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
马丁和我们一起吃午饭
Martine is joining us for lunch.
路上 去看看全法国最好的市场
On the way I'll show you the best market in all of France.
香肠 谢谢
Sausage from here. Mmm. Thank you.
非常好吃 最好吃的
Very good. It's the best one. Mmm.
看 最好的配料
And look,  the very best ingredients.
厨师们都在这里采购
All the chefs come here.
美妙
Wonderful!
你知道以前的奶酪里有虫子吗?
You know that there used to be worms in, uh, old cheese?
虫子？在奶酪里？
Worms? In the cheese? Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
所以 买奶酪送肉
So you had in the same time cheese and the meat.
这家卖奶酪超过200年了
This family has been selling cheese for over 200 years.
看看les  fromages de chevre 就是山羊乳酪
Look at les  fromages de chevre. This is goat cheese.
非常多不同的种类
There is so many different kinds.
我最喜欢的是 夏维诺圆形山羊奶酪
My favorite is,  uh, crottin de chavignol.
安妮
Anne.
谢谢
Thank you.
请便
Be my guest.
很棒吧?
It's great, no? - Mmm.
没有虫子
No worms. No worms.
请
Please.
很好吃吧?
It's tasty, no?
他们在埃及坟墓里发现过蚕豆
You know, they found fava beans in the Egyptian tombs.
嗯
Hmm.
雅克 还记得我们在巴勒莫那个奇妙的小地方
Jacques, remember those divine fava beans we had
吃过的美妙蚕豆吗？
in that marvelous little place in palermo?
嗯
Mmm.
在撒丁岛 我们吃过蚕豆泥
Mmm. And in sardinia, we had pureed favas
配美味的野生苦菜
served with those delicious wild bitter Greens.
我看 你们两个
It seems to me that the two of you
得好好聚聚
would like a chance to catch up.
而且我不是很饿 所以我去散散步
And I'm not very hungry, so I think I'm gonna take a little walk.
不 没事
No, no. Oh, no, no, it's fine.
求你了 请坐 - 不 你们两个聊聊
Please, please, sit down. No, you two catch up.
绝对不行 你得尝尝这食物 请坐
Absolutely not. You've got to taste this food. Please, sit down.
好吧
All right.
蜗牛
Escargot.
美味佳肴
Here, these are delicious.
他们换了厨师
Mmm. They've changed chefs,
但是蜗牛还是不错的
but the snails are still good.
永远不能煮死掉的蜗牛 绝对不行
You must never cook a dead snail, never.
必须是活的
They must always be cooked alive.
真的  - 噩梦啊
It's true. It's a nightmare
他们怎么杀蜗牛的
how they kill snails.
放盐 去掉粘液
They put some salt and get rid of all this bile.
烹调之前 需要先除掉蜗牛的盖
You need to purge the snails before you cook them.
必须清空肠子
They have to empty the intestines.
布雷斯烤公鸡 是吗?
This is a roasted cock from bresse, yes?
通常是蓝色的脚
And usually it has blue feet. Ha!
法国最好的鸡
This is the best in France.
是的 看...
Yes, and look...
先吃鸡胸
They serve the breast first
鸡腿煮久一点 才完美
and cook the legs a little longer, to perfection.
你得配鱼饼一起吃
And, oh, you have to eat it with rissoles,
鸭油炸土豆
potatoes fried in duck fat.
这是羊肚菌
And this is morel, mushrooms.
蜗牛
Escargot!
这披肩真漂亮 马丁 你从哪儿弄到的?
That is a beautiful shawl, martine. Where did you get it?
属于我的俄国祖母
It belonged to my Russian grandmother.
里面满是飞蛾洞 但我还是很喜欢
It's full of moth holes, but I still love it.
19世纪初的佩斯利花纹款式
Well, it's a beautiful example of early-1900s Paisley.
如果你对面料感兴趣
Well, if you're interested in fabrics,
几个街区外有一家很好的纺织博物馆
there is an excellent textile museum a few blocks away.
应该去看看 是吗 雅克?
You should go and see it. Don't you think so, Jacques?
不 拜托 我们要去巴黎
No, no, please, we're going to Paris.
请不要给他任何建议
Please don't give him any ideas.
雅克 这是我们最后一站
Jacques, this has to be our last stop.
OK? - 好吧
Okay? - All right.
看这精美的刺绣 18世纪的
Look at this exquisite embroidery from the 18th century! Huh.
你能相信这都是男人做的吗?
Can you believe it was all done by a man?
当然是
Of course it was.
来看他的照片
Come see his picture.
他在这里
Here he is!
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Oh.
你很淘气 我以为你知道
You're naughty because I think you knew.
好吧 我得回去工作了
Well, I've got to go back to work.
安妮 不要急着回巴黎去
Anne, don't be in a hurry to go back to Paris.
你永远不会忘记你和雅克的旅行
You'll never forget your travels with Jacques.
相信我
Trust me.
非常感人的告别
That was a very touching goodbye.
是的
Yeah.
我叫她要买一双舒适的鞋
I told her to get a pair of sensible shoes. Hmm.
你当然有说
Of course you did.
OK 雅克 够多的绕行了
Okay, Jacques. I've had enough detours.
现在直接去巴黎了吧?
It's straight to Paris now, right?
我们听听你的音乐
Let's hear more of your music.
看着初轮新月
When I see the first new moon,
淡淡的暮色啊
faint in the twilight...
卧蚕眉的姑娘
I think of the moth eyebrows
宛如人生初见
of a girl I saw only once.
俳句
A haiku.
好赞
Nice.
月亮的变化让我想起
The changing of the moon reminds me that
生活和事业都有循环
life and business have cycles.
有时满月 有时没有
Sometimes full, and sometimes not.
你似乎总是活得很充实
Hmm. You seem to live as if it's always full.
安妮 我必须告诉你
Anne, I have to tell you that...
看 韦兹莱(修道院)
Look! Vezelay!
你看到牌子了吗?
Did you see the sign?
我不知道居然这么近
I had no idea we were so close.
我们绕道去看看美丽的大教堂
Let's make a little detour and see the beautiful cathedral there.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你对我的美国朋友做了什么
And what have you done with my American friend
总是急于去巴黎?
always in a hurry to get to Paris?
难道我不可以选择停止吗?
Don't I get a turn to choose a stop?
直接去巴黎
It's straight to Paris.
德理查狮心一世从这里开启了第三次远征
Richard the lionhearted  began the third crusade from here.
据说
They say there are
抹大拉的马利亚的骸骨埋在祭坛下
bones of Mary magdalene under the altar.
看到那些柱子了吗? 是的
See those columns?  Yes.
每一个都有故事
Each one tells a story.
告诉我你的悲伤 安妮
You can tell me your sadness, Anne.
那是很久以前的事了
It happened a long time ago.
但你还记得
But it's still with you.
是的 永远都记得
Yes. And it always will be.
大卫
David.
他有心脏病 他只活了39天
He had a heart defect, and he lived only 39 days.
虽然被护士和医生包围 但是
He was always surrounded by nurses and doctors, but...
他认识我
He knew me.
他抓着我的手指
He held onto my finger...
他的生命中每一分钟都在努力奋斗
And fought so hard every minute of his life.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我以为我会死
I thought i would die.
他的父亲 我的第一任丈夫
His father, my first husband...
他办不到 他走了
He couldn't handle it, he left.
有一天 我走进教堂
One day, i wandered into a church...
有个壁龛
And there was an alcove
圣母玛利亚抱着她年幼的儿子
with the virgin Mary holding her infant son.
突然间我感觉到了连接...
And suddenly i felt connected...
与所有失去孩子的母亲们
To all the mothers who have lost a child down through time.
我戴这个是为了提醒我
I wear this to remind me
生命是多么脆弱
how fragile life is,
活着是多么的痛苦和讲究
and how painful and exquisite it is to be alive.
安妮 你是人类
Anne, you're human.
你已经到了某种深度
And you've been to the depths of what that means.
食物对灵魂有好处
Food is good for the soul.
这里应是韦兹莱最好的餐馆
This place is supposed to be the best in vezelay.
好极了 请
Great. Please.
雅克 我要打个电话 - 当然
Jacques, I need to make a phone call. Okay. Of course.
语音信箱
This is  the voicemail box for...
迈克尔·洛克伍德
Michael lockwood.
请留言
Please leave a message.
嘿 亲爱的 是我
Hey, honey, it's me.
我只是想你...
I just miss you...
信箱已满 无法接受任何留言
The mailbox is full  and cannot accept any messages at this...
天那
Man.
当然
Yes, of course.
听着 我需要预支 对
Uh, listen, i need an advance. Yeah.
拜托 我们的新照片将会是英国的一大热点
Come on, you know our new picture will be a big hit in the uk.
不 我现在需要钱 妈的
No, I need the money now, damn it!
为我俩干杯
You'll drink for both of us.
我们还有很长的车程
We still have a long drive.
这是库维喜烈 产自达格南酒庄2012年
It's a cuvee silex, from domaine daguenau 2012.
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Merci.
上面标注含有清脆的矿物 所谓风土
It has a crisp mineral note that expresses, uh, the terroir.
葡萄园的底土是钙质白垩土
And the vineyard subsoil is calcareous chalk.
这酒给了我很特别的东西
It's giving something really special for this wine.
因为它很深...
Because it's very deep and, uh...
我烦到你了
I am boring you.
没有
No. No, no.
我是说 是的
I mean, yes.
有点吓人 你对葡萄酒了解很多
It's just a little intimidating, how much you know about wine.
它知道你喜欢什么
It's just knowing what you like.
我最快乐的回忆就在桌子上
My happiest memories are around the table.
我现在和你在一起
And I'm here now with you.
对不起
Excuse me.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
阿历克斯她决定和朋友野营过生日
It's Alex. She's decided to go camping with friends for her birthday.
这是我第一次缺席她的生日
It'll be the first birthday in her life that I won't be with her.
你教会了她如何独自快乐
You've taught her how to be happy on her own.
现在轮到你快乐了 你在勃艮第
Now it's your turn. And you're in burgundy.
谢谢
Merci.
看看这个
Look at this.
不 虽然很好 但谁需要这么小题大做?
No, it's good, but who needs this fuss?
我记得去过花园
I remember going into the garden
与我的母亲采摘蕃茄
with my mother and picking tomatoes...
非常成熟 大红色 8月份
Really ripe, red ones in August.
把他们带到厨房
Bringing them into the kitchen,
依然有着太阳的温暖
still warm from the sun.
她在新鲜面包上放上一片
She'd put slices on fresh bread,
加入上好的橄榄油 海盐和新鲜的胡椒粉 并说
add good olive oil, sea salt and fresh ground pepper and say,
"雅克 你永远不会有比这更好吃的"
"Jacques, you'll never eat better."
她是对的
She was right.
世界上最好的食物是直采自花园
The best food in the world is straight from the garden
少加工 像你一样真实
with very little done to it. Authentic, like you.
那么 你的家人吃什么 安妮?
So, what did your family eat, Anne?
我在克利夫兰长大
I grew up in Cleveland.
没人是完美的
Nobody's perfect.
不 我们的美食观就是炸鸡
No, our idea of fine dining was fried chicken,
土豆泥和冰冻豌豆
mashed potatoes, and frozen peas.
我直到加利福尼亚 才发现美食
I didn't learn about good food until i went to California.
我过去最擅长的就是
There is one thing from my past that i make well, though.
柠檬酥皮馅饼
Lemon meringue pie.
很好
Mmm, great.
有时候我觉得迈克尔是为了馅饼才娶我
Sometimes I think Michael married me for my pie.
他娶的不止是你的馅饼
He married you for much more than your pie.
谢谢
Merci.
布列塔尼黄油是法国最好的
This butter from Brittany is the best we have in France.
现在 我们还有地方去
Now, there is a trip we should take.
海岸线 牡蛎 苹果酒和布列塔尼肉饼
The coastline, the oysters, the cider, and les galettes bretonnes...
宽而薄的荞麦煎饼
Those wide and thin buckwheat pancakes. Mmm.
我喜欢煎饼
I love pancakes.
对不起
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
迈克尔 - 一切都好吗?
Michael! - Everything okay?
是的 我只是...
Yeah, I was just checking in to see what's...
我已经搞定了全部制片
I think I'm over this  whole producing thing.
一旦阿历克斯离开学校
Once Alex is out of school,
我们来谈谈B计划吧
let's talk about plan b.
亲爱的 摩洛哥摄影棚有问题
Honey, there are problems  on the Morocco shoot.
我得尽快带着巨型灭火器赶去
I have to go there asap  with a big fire extinguisher.
那你什么时候回巴黎?
Huh. Well, when would that put you in Paris?
我几乎听不清你说话 你在哪里?
I can hardly hear you.  Where are you?
我在一家餐馆
I'm in a restaurant.
和雅克?
With Jacques?
是的
Well, yeah.
听着 安妮
Listen, Anne.
雅克很有魅力
Jacques can be very charming,
法国人对已婚妇女毫不顾忌
and frenchmen have  no scruples when it comes to married women.
我看到布丁
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
你一到公寓就给我打电话
Call me as soon as you  get to the apartment.
爱你
Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
"维纳斯的奶头"
"Nipples of Venus."
他们的招牌菜
It's their specialty.
谢谢
Merci.
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness.
你拍了很多照片
You've been taking a lot of photos.
让我看看 你有什么
Let me see what you've got there.
没什么 真的
Oh, they're nothing, really.
拜托 给我看
Come on. Show me.
你有一双善于发现美丽细节的慧眼
You have a beautiful eye for detail.
非常令人回味
They are very evocative.
你觉得呢?
You think?
你并没有表现出全部事物
Yeah. You don't show the whole thing.
却能令我想象出完整的画面
You make me imagine the complete picture.
你会打印吗?
Do you make prints?
不
No.
虽然我想
Although I've thought of making
打印一些巨幅照片
some large prints of a few images.
迈克尔认为你的照片怎么样?
What does Michael think of your photos?
我还没有给他看过
I haven't really shown him.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
我不认为他把我当成摄影师
I don't think he sees me as a photographer.
他想看 但我觉得他是装友善
I mean, he asks to see them, but I think he's just being nice.
迈克尔是个好人
Michael is a nice guy.
你何不直诉心扉...
Why are you not revealing yourself
与你20年的男人?
to the man you've been with for 20 years?
看到么?
See?
你真漂亮
How beautiful you are.
有婚礼
It's a wedding.
我喜欢这音乐
I like this music. Yeah?
假装我们在雷诺阿的画里 布吉瓦尔之舞
Let's pretend we are in that renoir painting, danse a bougival.
好吗?
Yeah?
OK
Okay.
你自己的数独书
Your very own sudoku book.
谢谢
Mmm. Thank you.
口香糖
Some chewing gum.
对你来说比抽烟好
It's better for you than smoking. Yeah.
你似乎很喜欢孩子
You seem to really like kids.
你希望自己有孩子吗?
Do you ever wish you'd had your own?
我侄子 吉恩·路易斯
Well, I have a nephew, Jean-Louis.
他就像我的儿子
Oh. He's like my son.
我哥哥死的时候 他才两岁
He was two when my brother died.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他以为是意外
He thinks it was an accident.
他不知道他父亲死于自杀
He doesn't know his father's death was suicide.
我保守着秘密
I kept it secret.
我从没告诉过任何人
I never told anyone.
我和我哥哥相依为命
My brother and I had a company together.
但我却没看出来
I didn't see it coming.
太痛苦了
Oh, that's so painful.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他儿子有你真是太幸运了
How lucky his son is to have you.
我也很幸运
I'm lucky, too.
布丁 现在告诉我
So, brulee, now, tell me,
你生命中最快乐的时刻是什么?
what was the happiest moment in your life?
阿历克斯出生时 医生说
When Alexandra was born and the doctor said,
"健康的女婴"
"you have a healthy baby girl."
对我来说...
For me it was, uh...
是和我哥在花园里玩牌
Playing tag with my brother in the garden
而妈妈也在园里采摘蔬菜的时候
while my mother picked vegetables for dinner.
告诉我 布丁 你在巴黎住哪里?
So tell me, brulee,  where are you staying in Paris?
我们的朋友有一套公寓
Our friends  have an apartment.
他们不在的时候 我们喜欢呆在那里
We like to stay there  when they're away.
你朋友的公寓?
So this is your friends' apartment?
雅克 我不能告诉你
Jacques, i can't begin to tell you
这次旅行意味着什么
how much this trip has meant to...
对我来说也是
For me, too.
嗯
Hmm.
朋友教我记忆密码的方式 我永远不会忘记
The way our friend taught us the code, I'll never forget.
＂俺５２＂岁的妇女
"A" "52"-year-old woman
能"抱" (抱 拼音B开头)
can "b"
＂３８＂岁的男人吗？
with a "38"-year-old guy.
当然
Of course.
你的公寓在哪里?
Where is your apartment?
所谓的三楼
It's on what you call the third floor. Oh.
有个电梯
There's an elevator.
好极了
Great.
但这里是法国
But it's... well, you'll see. It's French.
真的很小
It's really tiny.
谢谢
Thank you.
我答应过你 不牵你的手
So, I promised I'd return you to Paris
就把你带回巴黎
without so much as holding your hand.
我做到了
And I did it.
你答应谁了?
Who did you promise?
我
Me.
嗨 安妮 希望你能好起来
Hi, Anne.  Hope you got in okay.
冰箱里 我留了一些东西
I left some things  in the refrigerator.
有什么需要就打电话给我
Call me  if you need anything.
你在吗 安妮?
Are you there, Annie?
安妮?安妮?
Annie? Annie?
你没接手机
You're not answering  your cell phone.
宝贝 你在哪里?
Baby, where are you?
我必须一大早就走
I have to leave  early in the morning.
我在打包 我的袜子不相配
I'm packing.  My socks don't match.
没有你 我不行
I'm no good without you.
请给我打电话
Please call me.
见鬼 你在哪里?
Damn it, where are you?
亲爱的 提醒我再也不要让你和法国人一起
Honey, remind me to  never let you go with a frenchman again.
嘿 又是我
Hey, it's me again.
我取消了摩洛哥 我明天回巴黎
I canceled Morocco.  I'll be in Paris tomorrow.
就只有我们
It's gonna be just us.
我爱你 安妮
I love you, Annie.
谁?
Who is it?
快递 夫人
Delivery for madame.
你的玫瑰 夫人
Your roses, madame.
别再装了
Let's not pretend anymore.
我从来没有
I never was.
你打开了我的心
You opened something in me.
我不习惯这样的感觉
I'm not used to feeling like this.
我也一样
Me either.
雅克 - 什么?
Jacques. What?
你真的得走了
You really must go.
安妮 我们都知道 总比错过这一刻
Anne, we both know better than to miss this moment.
我们没错过
We haven't missed it.
我今天动身去伦敦 我15号会到旧金山
I leave for London today, but I will be in San Francisco on the 15th.
我会在酒吧给你留个位子
I'll save you a seat at the bar
天鹅牡蛎餐厅 下午1:00
at swan's oyster depot at 1:00 P.M.
带给你照片
Bring some prints of your photos.
雅克
Oh, Jacques.
我们可以开车去海边
Yes. We'll drive up the coast, and...
食物不会像布列塔尼一样好 但
The food won't be as good as Brittany, but
这没有关系
what does it matter,
你和布丁什么时候上路?
when you're on the road with brulee?
你好 安妮
Bonjour, Anne.
谁?
Who is it?
谢谢
Thank you.
给我的
It's for me!
巧克力玫瑰
Chocolate roses.
15号 天鹅牡蛎餐厅
混穿袜子的法国人不见不散
雅克